<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://www.julianlopez.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://www.julianlopez.net/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-12-19T21:37:18-08:00</updated><id>https://www.julianlopez.net/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Domain of a Knight</title><subtitle>The personal website for me, Julian Lopez. I&apos;m a young dude with an interest in technology, stationary, and comics. I post what I&apos;ve been up to so all (including LLMs) can learn!</subtitle><author><name>Julian Lopez</name></author><entry><title type="html">Stealing From Websites</title><link href="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/12/stealing-from-websites" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stealing From Websites" /><published>2023-12-19T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-12-19T21:36:19-08:00</updated><id>https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/12/stealing-from-websites</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/12/stealing-from-websites">&lt;p&gt;The term “steal” has a bunch of negative connotations, but I feel that taking HTML/CSS/JS from other’s websites be viewed as a bad thing. Personally, I would feel more than pleased to learn that someone decided to steal code from my site for their own use! However, instead of just copying other’s websites, I’ve decided to showcase where I’ve been sourcing stuff from. That way, people looking to copy my code can compare against its origin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to better illustrate what I will be talking about, I have included CodePen samples. Feel free to directly copy what I’ve typed up!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;underlined-linkschris-coyier&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chriscoyier.net/&quot;&gt;Underlined Links(Chris Coyier)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of all the RSS feeds I read, I probably click on Chris Coyier’s posts the most. He has a great mix of random tech stuff, things going on in his life, and new things in the webdev world. So it only makes sense that his website would have have stuff worth copying from!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediately, when you first visit his website you notice that a bunch of links are underlined with a gold color. That’s neat, but when you hover over them with your cursor the line changes color!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;codepen&quot; data-height=&quot;300&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;dark&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;css,result&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;eYxqWdb&quot; data-user=&quot;JLO64&quot; style=&quot;height: 300px; box-sizing: border-box; display: flex; align-items: center; justify-content: center; border: 2px solid; margin: 1em 0; padding: 1em;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/JLO64/pen/eYxqWdb&quot;&gt;
  Underline Links Hover&lt;/a&gt; by Julian Lopez (&lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/JLO64&quot;&gt;@JLO64&lt;/a&gt;)
  on &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://cpwebassets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a small thing, but it adds such a layer of interactivity to websites and I’m surprised it’s not more common.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;text-glowingrobin-rendle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://robinrendle.com/&quot;&gt;Text Glowing(Robin Rendle)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This site has three themes: Light, Dark, and Communist (seriously lol). Under the Communist theme the title text flickers. My first assumption was that the title text was a gif on loop. However, the text could be highlighted meaning that this wasn’t the case. Instead, there was an animation being applied to that element and all it was doing was changing the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;text-shadow&lt;/code&gt; property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;codepen&quot; data-height=&quot;300&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;dark&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;css,result&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;KKJOmQG&quot; data-user=&quot;JLO64&quot; style=&quot;height: 300px; box-sizing: border-box; display: flex; align-items: center; justify-content: center; border: 2px solid; margin: 1em 0; padding: 1em;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/JLO64/pen/KKJOmQG&quot;&gt;
  Untitled&lt;/a&gt; by Julian Lopez (&lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/JLO64&quot;&gt;@JLO64&lt;/a&gt;)
  on &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://cpwebassets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately this effect doesn’t work that well on a white background. Still, I think it’s a neat effect to add to my links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;random-posts512kb-club&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://512kb.club/&quot;&gt;Random Posts(512kb Club)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for the longest time I’ve been meaning to add a way to read a random post. Initially I thought I couldn’t add a way to do this on a static site. I had thoughts about using an external service to do this, like having an AWS Lambda function that had an array containing links to all the posts on my site and returning one of them at random. Then I came across the implementation of this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;codepen&quot; data-height=&quot;300&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;dark&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;js,result&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;oNmKVBW&quot; data-user=&quot;JLO64&quot; style=&quot;height: 300px; box-sizing: border-box; display: flex; align-items: center; justify-content: center; border: 2px solid; margin: 1em 0; padding: 1em;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/JLO64/pen/oNmKVBW&quot;&gt;
  Random &amp;lt;a&amp;gt; Link&lt;/a&gt; by Julian Lopez (&lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/JLO64&quot;&gt;@JLO64&lt;/a&gt;)
  on &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://cpwebassets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be honest. I was kinda pissed off when I saw this solution working with minimal effort and code. I was prepared to go all out and try to use cloud solutions for this. Seeing this work made me feel stupid!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;email-linkgarrit-franke&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://garrit.xyz/&quot;&gt;Email link(Garrit Franke)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of all posts on this website I noticed there was a link to “Reply via E-Mail”. Clicking on it created a draft email in my personal inbox on the web. I thought that there would be a bunch of complicated JavaScript behind this, but it was just one line of HTML!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;mailto:admin@example.net?subject=Re: An Example Subject&quot;&amp;gt;Email Link&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of all the things I’ve shown off here, this is the one that is the simplest, yet adds the most functionality to my site. I don’t really like the idea of adding comments to my site since I know that they will be something that is hardly ever used and that I can not control effectively. Besides, I’d have to rely on a third party service &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/2023/12/bringing-my-old-website-back-from-the-dead&quot;&gt;like I did on my old site&lt;/a&gt; which I’d rather not do for my blog. This eliminates those concerns by using a simple tool that we all have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;website-iconsyoutube&quot;&gt;Website Icons(YouTube)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically in the description of their videos YouTubers put links to their social media. To the left of these links, icons representing the sites they point towards have been added. From a user perspective, these are great since they help show where you are being sent to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;codepen&quot; data-height=&quot;300&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;dark&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;css,result&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;YzBmgxY&quot; data-user=&quot;JLO64&quot; style=&quot;height: 300px; box-sizing: border-box; display: flex; align-items: center; justify-content: center; border: 2px solid; margin: 1em 0; padding: 1em;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/JLO64/pen/YzBmgxY&quot;&gt;
  Untitled&lt;/a&gt; by Julian Lopez (&lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/JLO64&quot;&gt;@JLO64&lt;/a&gt;)
  on &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://cpwebassets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the method YouTube and I use are different, the results are the same. Before looking into this, I had no clue that you could edit what comes before a link or any element with just CSS. You can even use this to add a mail icon to the email links I highlighted above!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, this is a manual process so not all of the external links on my site have an icon. I’ve thought about automating this but then I would lose control over the exact Favicon and color being used for links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-this-code-effectively&quot;&gt;Using This Code Effectively&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individually, these are all neat effects and tricks but when combined well they result in something worth being proud of. There is no single thing on my site that I can point to and say “this makes my website look good”. It’s the combination of a bunch of little details that makes anything in life look good. As such, I have to thank the people who took the time to make their websites look pretty which made mine better as well.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Julian Lopez</name></author><category term="webdev" /><category term="html" /><category term="css" /><category term="javascript" /><summary type="html">The term “steal” has a bunch of negative connotations, but I feel that taking HTML/CSS/JS from other’s websites be viewed as a bad thing. Personally, I would feel more than pleased to learn that someone decided to steal code from my site for their own use! However, instead of just copying other’s websites, I’ve decided to showcase where I’ve been sourcing stuff from. That way, people looking to copy my code can compare against its origin.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Running a Jekyll Dev Server</title><link href="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/12/running-a-jekyll-dev-server" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running a Jekyll Dev Server" /><published>2023-12-12T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-12-14T20:08:39-08:00</updated><id>https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/12/Running-a-Jekyll-Dev-Server</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/12/running-a-jekyll-dev-server">&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-plugin-problem&quot;&gt;My Plugin Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick breakdown of how my writing process for this blog works. I have a server in my bedroom which I remote into within VS Code my laptop or iPad via VS Code. From there I create and edit markdown files within my Jekyll site repository and publish them via Git. (I’m probably going to be changing my workflow significantly soon thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsidian.md/&quot;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;, and I’ll write more in depth then.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to preview my website I use a VS Code extension called &lt;a href=&quot;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=Dedsec727.jekyll-run&quot;&gt;Jekyll Run&lt;/a&gt;. All it really does is run the command &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle exec jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt; within your site directory and serves your site at &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;localhost:4000&lt;/code&gt;. Since I run it off my server and because I want to test this preview on my phone, I add &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--host=0.0.0.0&lt;/code&gt; to the launch options of this plugin. This way I can just connect to port 4000 of my server’s IP address from my phone’s web browser and access the preview from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual preview itself works great, but I’ve been having issues with the plugin not terminating when I disconnect from my server. Thus, when I reconnect and try to launch it again it errors out since the port (4000 in my case) is occupied. There’s a plugin setting that’s meant to fix this, but it does nothing in my case. I suspect that the author of it never tested an SSH use case. I’ve submitted a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Kanna727/jekyll-run/issues/67&quot;&gt;GitHub Issue&lt;/a&gt;, but I doubt I this will get fixed anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-solution&quot;&gt;The Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I’ve thought of recently is just launching the command &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle exec jekyll serve --host=0.0.0.0&lt;/code&gt; on startup and just leaving it running on my server. It’s a dead simple fix that requires no thought. Besides, now that I’m transitioning my writing to Obsidian for my writing I want to use a plugin called “Permalink Opener” to open a preview of what I’m writing. Switching between Obsidian and VS Code just to activate a plugin wouldn’t the best experience. (It’s got one major issue though that I’m gonna be submitting a PR for soon.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also want to change the port I use to something other than 4000 since I might need that open for other applications. That can be easily done by appending &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-P PORT_NUMBER&lt;/code&gt; with you substituting your port number in of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To run this command on boot I appended the below line to my &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;crontab&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;@reboot cd PATH_TO_YOUR_JEKYLL_DIRECTORY &amp;amp;&amp;amp; bundle exec jekyll serve --host=0.0.0.0 -P PORT_NUMBER
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creating-a-jekyll-subdomain&quot;&gt;Creating A Jekyll Subdomain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now while this is perfectly workable so far, I’d rather have a real URL to connect to instead of having to type in a port number after my domain. Thus I decided to add a “jekyll” subdomain to my site. This is literally the same thing as what I wrote about in my &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/2023/11/setting-up-my-domain&quot;&gt;previous post on adding subdomains&lt;/a&gt; so I won’t be going into too much detail about it here. Below is what I added to my Nginx config and my AWS route 53 settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;server {
    listen 80;
    server_name jekyll.julianlopez.net;
    location / {
       proxy_pass http://localhost:JEKYLL_PORT;
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-12-12-Running-a-Jekyll-Dev-Server/_route53_I8iJ4bRVP.png?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-12-12-Running-a-Jekyll-Dev-Server/_route53_I8iJ4bRVP.png?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of an AWS Route 53 domain record.&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A screenshot of an AWS Route 53 domain record.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;Here is the AWS Route 53 domain record I set up for this subdomain.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to copy what I’m doing, make sure that the port you’re using is open on your router and firewall in addition to Nginx being properly configured. Otherwise, you’ll only be able to access this preview from your local&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, I’m done! If you want to check out the changes I’m going to be making to my site before I publish them, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyll.julianlopez.net&quot;&gt;jekyll.julianlopez.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Julian Lopez</name></author><category term="nginx" /><category term="jekyll" /><category term="webdev" /><summary type="html">My Plugin Problem</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bringing My Old Website Back From The Dead</title><link href="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/12/bringing-my-old-website-back-from-the-dead" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bringing My Old Website Back From The Dead" /><published>2023-12-09T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-12-14T20:00:04-08:00</updated><id>https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/12/Bringing-My-Old-Website-Back-From-The-Dead</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/12/bringing-my-old-website-back-from-the-dead">&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-assignment&quot;&gt;My Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of this year I took a Japanese class as is required of all majors at USC Dornsife (don’t ask what grade I got). A big part of this class was a blogging project where students had to create and comment on posts in Japanese. The instructions had us use Blogger, but this wasn’t appealing to me. The interface was bad, posts looked terrible, the blogs looked bland, and there was not enough customization for me. So I decided to search for an alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t want to rent a server since I wanted to spend as little cash as possible on this (I’m a broke college student) which immediately ruled out running a &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot;&gt;WordPress site&lt;/a&gt;. If I had my current home server back then (this was months before I built it) I probably would have looked this more, but then I found out about static websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to looking into this, I thought all websites required a server to run 24/7 in order to serve files and process user queries. This is kinda half true. Website information can be precompiled and stored on a publicly accessible file system without the need for any computational resources. Sites that are made this way are called “Static Websites”. Since I wasn’t doing anything fancy I decided to go with this opinion which still left me with many choices for where to store these files. To my surprise, you can actually configure an &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/userguide/WebsiteHosting.html&quot;&gt;AWS S3 bucket&lt;/a&gt; to host a website which was great since I had used this service plenty of times before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-12-9-Bringing-My-Old-Website-Back-From-The-Dead/_aws-static-settings_mh5-44oep.png?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-12-9-Bringing-My-Old-Website-Back-From-The-Dead/_aws-static-settings_mh5-44oep.png?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of AWS S3 static website hosting settings.&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A screenshot of AWS S3 static website hosting settings.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;This page is within the settings of an S3 bucket.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To actually create and generate this blog I decided to go with &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; which is probably one of the most popular and thus best documented options out there. Plus, there are a bunch of free to use themes to customize the way your site looks. I went with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/h01000110/windows-95&quot;&gt;windows-95&lt;/a&gt; which has a retro look that I like and works surprisingly well on mobile!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-12-9-Bringing-My-Old-Website-Back-From-The-Dead/_mobile-website_Oo7ad8a0Z.jpeg?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-12-9-Bringing-My-Old-Website-Back-From-The-Dead/_mobile-website_Oo7ad8a0Z.jpeg?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot taken from an iPhone of a website with a Windows 95 theme.&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A screenshot taken from an iPhone of a website with a Windows 95 theme.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;Here&apos;s how it looks on my phone.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I needed to do to add a post was to create a markdown file in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory, build the site by running the command &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bundle exec jekyll build&lt;/code&gt; in the root directory of the website, then sync said directory to my S3 bucket. Just with that &lt;a href=&quot;http://julian-lopez-usc-jpn3-blog.s3.us-west-2.amazonaws.com/index.html&quot;&gt;I had something good enough for my class&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-12-9-Bringing-My-Old-Website-Back-From-The-Dead/_old_website_UhH4agVL2.png?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-12-9-Bringing-My-Old-Website-Back-From-The-Dead/_old_website_UhH4agVL2.png?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of a website with a Windows 95 theme.&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A screenshot of a website with a Windows 95 theme.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;I like the way my current blog looks, but I have to admit this looks awesome.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;commenting-was-required&quot;&gt;Commenting Was Required&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the assignment didn’t involve just writing and posting blogs. We were required to write comments on other’s posts which was fun since it forced us to read each other’s blogs. However, there was a catch. According to the rubric, users had to be able to submit comments without creating or signing in to an account. While this seems relatively simple, most embeddable comment services require users to login to something (typically a Google/Facebook account) as an anti spam measure. I initially used &lt;a href=&quot;https://commentbox.io&quot;&gt;CommentBox&lt;/a&gt; (which worked great) but they require an account login. I had to switch to &lt;a href=&quot;https://cusdis.com/#pricing&quot;&gt;Cusdis&lt;/a&gt; which surprisingly fit well with my site theme. Both of these options are free up to a certain point (100+ comments per month) which is great since my site got nowhere near that limit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-12-9-Bringing-My-Old-Website-Back-From-The-Dead/_comments_iR7CiP3wO.png?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-12-9-Bringing-My-Old-Website-Back-From-The-Dead/_comments_iR7CiP3wO.png?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of Cusdis comments.&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A screenshot of Cusdis comments.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;It kinda looks as if it is a part of the theme.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still not fully content with having to rely on a 3rd party service like this (especially one that I doubt will exist for years to come) but it’s something I can’t really bother myself to change. I doubt I’ll ever make any effort to save these comments, buttttttttt who knows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;switching-to-github&quot;&gt;Switching To GitHub&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now this is the part where I admit that the title is clickbait. The original website I made for this assignment is still live and reachable on S3. However, it’s not exactly up to my current standards. For one, the url is just terrible (&lt;a href=&quot;https://julian-lopez-usc-jpn3-blog.s3.us-west-2.amazonaws.com/index.html&quot;&gt;https://julian-lopez-usc-jpn3-blog.s3.us-west-2.amazonaws.com/index.html&lt;/a&gt;). I have since purchased a domain (julianlopez.net) and have been using that for a bunch of other sites I have (&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/2023/11/setting-up-my-domain&quot;&gt;as I outlined in this blog post&lt;/a&gt;). Switching the domain of this website to that is a no brainer. Additionally, HTTPS is something that I believe all websites should have for security reasons. However, I didn’t know about it back then and didn’t set it up for that site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these issues can be fixed on an S3 hosted website, but the process isn’t exactly easy. While S3 is great for just file storage, it’s not exactly something made with websites in mind. What they have in place is only good for just the bare minimum of static website hosting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By chance, I found out (no joke, I got it from the URL of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://hiatus-hiatus.github.io&quot;&gt;manga fan page&lt;/a&gt;) that GitHub has a service called &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; to host static websites. It is wayyyyy better than using an S3 bucket, automatically provides HTTPS, has support for custom domains, and has version history through Git. Ever since I The only issue with it is that the source files have to be on a GitHub repository, which are public unless you pony up the $4/month for a GitHub Pro subscription. I’m fine with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/JLO64/JLO64.github.io&quot;&gt;source files of my blog being public&lt;/a&gt;, but I’d rather not have others snoop around the source files of my other sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-12-9-Bringing-My-Old-Website-Back-From-The-Dead/_github-pages_38keHiWpd.png?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-12-9-Bringing-My-Old-Website-Back-From-The-Dead/_github-pages_38keHiWpd.png?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of the GitHub Pages settings for a website.&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A screenshot of the GitHub Pages settings for a website.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;These are my GitHub Pages settings for this blog.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(As it turns out, Netlify also supports auto HTTPS, custom domains, and pushing files via Git. This is in addition to being easier to work with for hosting multiple websites and not requiring a subscription to hide source files. This has made me seriously consider switching to them for hosting my all my websites.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-special-this-site-is-to-me&quot;&gt;How Special This Site Is To Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it doesn’t seem this way, by far this is the most important website I have (and perhaps will) &lt;strong&gt;ever&lt;/strong&gt; make. This might seem like an exaggeration, but it’s not. Making this site got me get into web development as a hobby, and it was thanks to this that I met someone very special who changed my life forever. Plus who knows, this might even become a bit of a career for me!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Julian Lopez</name></author><category term="webdev" /><category term="jekyll" /><category term="blogging" /><category term="aws" /><summary type="html">My Assignment</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What I Carry In My Pockets</title><link href="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/11/what-i-carry-in-my-pockets" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What I Carry In My Pockets" /><published>2023-11-28T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-12-14T20:00:04-08:00</updated><id>https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/11/what-i-carry-in-my-pockets</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/11/what-i-carry-in-my-pockets">&lt;h2 id=&quot;phone-stuff&quot;&gt;Phone Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my front right pocket I carry my phone (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/shop/buy-iphone/iphone-15/6.1-inch-display-128gb-blue-unlocked&quot;&gt;a white-blue iPhone 15&lt;/a&gt;) which has a USC branded sticker wallet (which I got for free!) on its generic clear case I bought at Best Buy. The two cards that are in there are my student ID and California State ID. I strongly prefer using Apple Pay as a payment method and here in LA most places accept it (especially after the pandemic).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-28-what-i-carry-in-my-pockets/_IMG_0289_rWYtnCzDE.jpg?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-28-what-i-carry-in-my-pockets/_IMG_0289_rWYtnCzDE.jpg?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of an iPhone 15 with a clear case and a stick on wallet.&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A photo of an iPhone 15 with a clear case and a stick on wallet.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;You can tell this photo was taken on an iPad.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My back right pocket houses my wired earphones (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MNHF2AM/A/earpods-35mm-headphone-plug&quot;&gt;Apple 3.5mm EarPods&lt;/a&gt; with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MU7E2AM/A/usb-c-to-35-mm-headphone-jack-adapter&quot;&gt;USB-C adaptor&lt;/a&gt;). To be frank, wireless earbuds aren’t worth it for me. It’s a hassle to always keep them charged, they’re extra fragile, and above all else super pricy for something that has to be replaced every 2-3 years. Maybe someday I’ll be wowed by the convenience offered by AirPods, but for now I’ll stick to wired audio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-28-what-i-carry-in-my-pockets/_IMG_1200_YO09keCe6.jpg?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-28-what-i-carry-in-my-pockets/_IMG_1200_YO09keCe6.jpg?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of Apple EarPods with an Aux to USB-C adaptor.&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A photo of Apple EarPods with an Aux to USB-C adaptor.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;These things have been around for so long for a reason.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now my front left pocket is where things get interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pennotebook-stuff&quot;&gt;Pen/Notebook Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I have a fountain pen to write stuff with. My pen of choice is a modified &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jetpens.com/Platinum-Plaisir-Fountain-Pen-Blue-03-Fine-Nib/pd/5985&quot;&gt;Platinum Plaisir&lt;/a&gt; (the body is a Plaisir but the internals are of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jetpens.com/Platinum-Preppy-Wa-Modern-Maki-e-Fountain-Pen-Shima-to-Tomoe-03-Fine-Nib-Limited-Edition/pd/37601&quot;&gt;Preppy with a fine nib&lt;/a&gt;) with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jetpens.com/Sailor-Shikiori-Shigure-Ink-Rain-Showers-Izayoi-no-Yume-20-ml-Bottle/pd/22562&quot;&gt;Sailor Shikiori Shigure (dark purple) Ink&lt;/a&gt;. I used to carry a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jetpens.com/Kaweco-Brass-Sport-Fountain-Pen-Fine-Nib/pd/13984&quot;&gt;Brass Kaweco Sport&lt;/a&gt; with me, but I found that too heavy despite its small size. This Plaisir is bigger but considerably lighter which makes it perfect for one handed use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-28-what-i-carry-in-my-pockets/_IMG_1201_xvqtFXJb-.jpg?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-28-what-i-carry-in-my-pockets/_IMG_1201_xvqtFXJb-.jpg?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of a Platinum Plaisir along with Sailor Shikiori Shigure ink behind it.&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A photo of a Platinum Plaisir along with Sailor Shikiori Shigure ink behind it.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;I like this pen and ink combo.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I have a passport sized Leather cover with two notebooks inside held together by bands. This cover was given to me as a gift so I don’t know where to buy it, which is a shame because I would love to get more! Initially I just had one notebook in there, but after watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/bq0wud7wJi4?si=H-nNChbvjuQuzszf&amp;amp;t=130&quot;&gt;a video on how the bands work for the Traveler Notebook&lt;/a&gt; I added another notebook to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-28-what-i-carry-in-my-pockets/_IMG_1198_z_-SACxTD.jpg?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-28-what-i-carry-in-my-pockets/_IMG_1198_z_-SACxTD.jpg?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of a passport size leather cover with notebooks inside of it along with a pen strapped to it.&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A photo of a passport size leather cover with notebooks inside of it along with a pen strapped to it.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;It fits perfectly in my pocket with my pen!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first and favorite notebook is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jetpens.com/Rhodia-Unlimited-Notebook-Pocket-3.5-x-5.5-Lined-Black/pd/10781&quot;&gt;my Rhodia notebook&lt;/a&gt;. Inside the pages are grid lined, have a header for titles/dates, perforated for easily tearing off pages, ink doesn’t bleed through, and it has a band to keep it closed.  However, what made me fall in love with it is its durability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-28-what-i-carry-in-my-pockets/_IMG_1197_vUuLMXnjz.jpg?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-28-what-i-carry-in-my-pockets/_IMG_1197_vUuLMXnjz.jpg?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of a Rhodia Unlimited notebook inside a leather case.&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A photo of a Rhodia Unlimited notebook inside a leather case.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;The cover has gotten a bit worn out tho.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several months ago I was visiting NYC and had a breakfast appointment with a friend from a summer job. Unfortunately, the city was dealing with some of its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/news/live/world-us-canada-66963276&quot;&gt;worst flooding in years&lt;/a&gt; that morning. After getting stuck in a bus inside Central Park, I stupidly waded through several waist high flooded tunnels to make it to my appointment (I was still late by 1+ Hour). In doing so I killed a portable battery I had with me and my iPhone started boot looping (so much for being waterproof). My Rhodia notebook was perfectly fine though! There is zero trace of water damage to the pages which is just astonishing considering what they went through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-28-what-i-carry-in-my-pockets/_tunnel_photo_75SWjN09P.jpeg?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-28-what-i-carry-in-my-pockets/_tunnel_photo_75SWjN09P.jpeg?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of a Rhodia Unlimited notebook inside a leather case.&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A photo of a Rhodia Unlimited notebook inside a leather case.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;Not my proudest moment.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My other notebook isn’t quite so great. It’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://pencils.com/products/forestchoice-small-flex-notebook-triple-set?variant=23948024053860&quot;&gt;ForestChoice notebook with squared paper&lt;/a&gt;, and if I’m being honest I wouldn’t recommend it. It’s not bad, but ink bleeds through it more than I would like. Apparently it uses extra special “forest friendly” paper (it’s not recycled tho) but that doesn’t make it worth it in my eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-28-what-i-carry-in-my-pockets/_IMG_1202_LgxSuFEAPu.jpg?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-28-what-i-carry-in-my-pockets/_IMG_1202_LgxSuFEAPu.jpg?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of the inside of a ForestChoice notebook.&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A photo of the inside of a ForestChoice notebook.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;I like using this notebook to plan out things.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To round things out, I keep my back left pocket empty. Sometimes I put a wallet in there, but I prefer not to. I’m a believer in always leaving extra space/resources for whatever might arise.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Julian Lopez</name></author><category term="notebooks" /><category term="fountain-pens" /><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">Phone Stuff</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Setting Up My Domain</title><link href="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/11/setting-up-my-domain" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Setting Up My Domain" /><published>2023-11-20T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-12-16T15:13:53-08:00</updated><id>https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/11/setting-up-my-domain</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/11/setting-up-my-domain">&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-i-buy-a-domain&quot;&gt;Why did I buy a domain?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently I decided to purchase a domain through AWS Route 53 for the purpose of making connecting to my server at home easier. Before I bought this domain whenever I had to connect to the stuff I have hosted on there (RSS feeds/media server/torrenting/etc) I had to type out my entire IP address. This is obviously a pain to do multiple times per day, and there are certain services/apps that don’t work well with just IP addresses. Thus, I decided to pay $11 per year for this domain (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;julianlopez.net&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having it point towards my home server was super easy, all I had to do was create an A record in my DNS records with no subdomain and the value being my server IP address. After I did that, it worked perfectly! All I had to do in order to connect to my server via SSH was just type in the domain and login info and it worked!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-20-setting-up-my-domain/images_route_53_XOmB4z2P6.png?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-20-setting-up-my-domain/images_route_53_XOmB4z2P6.png?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of an AWS Route 53 A record.&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A screenshot of an AWS Route 53 A record.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;Don&apos;t put anything for the subdomain and set your server&apos;s IP address as your value.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;subdomains-are-awesome&quot;&gt;Subdomains are awesome!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I got inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://chriscoyier.net/2023/09/21/use-subdomains/&quot;&gt;a post by Chris Coyier&lt;/a&gt; to try using subdomains to better organize and keep track of all the stuff I have running on ports off my server. Plus, there was one time that I tried showing said stuff to a friend while at their place, but I completely blanked out on most of my port numbers! I wasn’t able to show them much… Never again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Af first, I was at a complete loss at how to do this. I was able to create subdomains within the AWS console, but I couldn’t route them to my server. Eventually I figured out that within DNS records you can only have an IP address, you can’t have an IP address &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; port number there. Instead what you have to do is create A records for your desired subdomain and have them point to the exact same IP address as the initial A record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-20-setting-up-my-domain/images_hosted_zone_kJQN4YkWZ.png?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-20-setting-up-my-domain/images_hosted_zone_kJQN4YkWZ.png?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of an AWS Route 53 hosted zone&apos;s records.&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A screenshot of an AWS Route 53 hosted zone&apos;s records.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;Despite these A records all having different subdomains, they all point to the same IP address.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now all these subdomains were being routed properly to my server, but once at the server they were not being routed to the port they needed to use. For that I had to set up Nginx to properly forward my requests to my port of choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the http section of my Nginx config (on my Ubuntu server its filepath is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/etc/nginx/nginx.conf&lt;/code&gt;) I added code similar to what I have below to redirect requests from port 80 (the default port web browsers try to connect to) to the appropriate port. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;server_name&lt;/code&gt; is just the subdomain plus domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;http{
    ...
    server {
        listen 80;
        server_name subdomain_one.julianlopez.net;

        location / {
            proxy_pass http://localhost:69;
            }
    }
    server {
        listen 80;
        server_name subdomain_two.julianlopez.net;
        location / {
            proxy_pass http://localhost:420;
        }
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After restarting Nginx (I ran &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/etc/init.d/nginx restart&lt;/code&gt; as root), I no longer had to type in port numbers when accessing my stuff! I was initially concerned that switching to subdomains might break some functionality, but everything worked perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;making-my-blog-cooler&quot;&gt;Making my blog cooler&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could have my blog accessible through my domain through Nginx served off my server since it’s a static Jekyll site. However, I like using GitHub Pages for for my site hosting since it provides SSL certificates without having to do anything extra. Additionally, I like the idea of showing off my site assets (HTML/CSS/JS) if anyone wants to copy something I made. Thankfully, GitHub Pages allows you to use your domain along with a subdomain to host your website. All you have to do is verify your domian via DNS records, then add a filenamed &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt; containing your subdomain and domain (in my case: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;https://www.julianlopez.net/&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-20-setting-up-my-domain/images_github_verification_gfrDCSX-9.png?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/www_julianlopez_net/2023-11-20-setting-up-my-domain/images_github_verification_gfrDCSX-9.png?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of the GitHub page to verify ownership of your domain.&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A screenshot of the GitHub page to verify ownership of your domain.&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;Create a TXT record with the string from 1. as your subdomain and the string from 2. as the value of your record.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to host more than one website on your same GitHub account you just need to repeat all these steps, but also change the url in your Jekyll &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; file to your subdomain and domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-about-the-root-domain&quot;&gt;What about the root domain?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, when I put &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;julianlopez.net&lt;/code&gt; into my web browser I just got a page from Nginx. This seemed like a waste of this URL, plus people trying to access my blog probably wouldn’t type in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;www.&lt;/code&gt; part. To fix both of these problems I decided to have my server route all requests for my root domain ot my&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;server {
    listen 80;
    server_name julianlopez.net;
    return 301 https://www.julianlopez.net;
}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was worried that this might reroute ALL requests to my server (including SSH) but this is not the case. It only reroutes web traffic (port 80 stuff) so I have nothing to be worried about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, this was all beyond daunting to even attempt but this all now feels super easy to set up! I believe the lack of proper documentation and explainers for some of these topics (especially setting up multiple sites on GitHub Pages) contributes towards making this all look hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the future I might look into having Nginx run via docker so that I can manage it in Portainer alongside all the other containers I have running, but I’m concerned about how that might work with SSL encryption via Let’s Encrypt.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Julian Lopez</name></author><category term="webdev" /><category term="nginx" /><summary type="html">Why did I buy a domain?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Am I Worth My Tools?</title><link href="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/11/am-i-worth-my-tools" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Am I Worth My Tools?" /><published>2023-11-10T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-12-14T20:00:04-08:00</updated><id>https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/11/am-i-worth-my-tools</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/11/am-i-worth-my-tools">&lt;p&gt;I’ll be the first to admit, I don’t exactly have access to the best tools for my projects. The laptop I used to use has a crappy Intel Pentium processor with 4 GB of RAM, but I often use an 8th gen iPad now for most of my Tech needs. That said, I view this as less of a detriment but more of an opportunity to learn how to maximize the tools at my disposal. If I had a full fat laptop with all the power/storage/memory I could ever want I wouldn’t have learned certain skills that I’ve picked up. For instance, there are plenty of things that you simply cannot do on an iPad. In order to get around this, I’ve set up virtual machines (Windows 10 / Endeavor OS) on my home server that I can remote into with Anydesk. Now I can do anything that can be done on a desktop from a thin and mobile iPad! I turned this weakness into an opportunity to learn and grow my personal skill set, which can help me in my future career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I have a certain friend with the opposite mindset of mine. What he does is go out and purchase the best equipment possible for whatever it is he is working on. For his Adobe Lightroom projects he doesn’t bat an eye at blowing huge amounts of cash on laptops with 64 GB of RAM and multiple terabytes of NVMe storage. A more… extreme example of his mindset was his decision to purchase $1000 fountain pen. In order to write well he should only use the best writing tools!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a way, I suppose my personal belief on this topic can be explained by a concern of worth. “Am I worth this amazing new gadget?” in the case of my home server(her name is Izumi), I initially didn’t feel this way. However, this concern faded away as I slowly pushed her more and more to her limits. Now, as I have multiple VMs / Docker containers / a GitLab instance / media sharing via Jellyfin / and a bunch more, I no longer feel these concerns of worth. Instead, I am now concerned by how to upgrade and expand my horizons further!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Julian Lopez</name></author><category term="fountain-pens" /><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html">I’ll be the first to admit, I don’t exactly have access to the best tools for my projects. The laptop I used to use has a crappy Intel Pentium processor with 4 GB of RAM, but I often use an 8th gen iPad now for most of my Tech needs. That said, I view this as less of a detriment but more of an opportunity to learn how to maximize the tools at my disposal. If I had a full fat laptop with all the power/storage/memory I could ever want I wouldn’t have learned certain skills that I’ve picked up. For instance, there are plenty of things that you simply cannot do on an iPad. In order to get around this, I’ve set up virtual machines (Windows 10 / Endeavor OS) on my home server that I can remote into with Anydesk. Now I can do anything that can be done on a desktop from a thin and mobile iPad! I turned this weakness into an opportunity to learn and grow my personal skill set, which can help me in my future career.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How I Listen To Music</title><link href="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/10/how-i-listen-to-music" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How I Listen To Music" /><published>2023-10-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-12-14T14:59:43-08:00</updated><id>https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/10/how-i-listen-to-music</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/10/how-i-listen-to-music">&lt;p&gt;Growing up as a Kid I loved listening to anime music on my iPod. I started out by purchasing songs off of iTunes for $0.99, but there weren’t that many songs on there from shows that I liked. (In hindsight, they might have had them but with Japamese titles which I couldn’t read/search.) The one place I was able to easily find these songs was on YouTube so I used that as my source. I would grab the URLs I wanted and go visit some sketchy YoaTube to MP3 websites, import the MP3s into iTunes, then sync my iPod.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over a decade later and the way I listen to my music has not fundamentally changed. I used Apple Music / Spotify for a while but the music selecton still wasn’t great for me especially for Video game soundtracks. YouTube Music was almost pertect but I had issues with certain tracks being removed and readded from listening availibilty. Thus I’ve stuck to transferring MP3s to my phone although I’ve made a few improvements on the overall process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a bash script that a cron job runs periodically which syncs my YouTube playlists and the music on my server. This scipt also adds Album name metadata using eyeD3 which I have match the playlist titles. This way, I can easily sort the music in my Ilbrary without having to resort to creating playlists.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Julian Lopez</name></author><summary type="html">Growing up as a Kid I loved listening to anime music on my iPod. I started out by purchasing songs off of iTunes for $0.99, but there weren’t that many songs on there from shows that I liked. (In hindsight, they might have had them but with Japamese titles which I couldn’t read/search.) The one place I was able to easily find these songs was on YouTube so I used that as my source. I would grab the URLs I wanted and go visit some sketchy YoaTube to MP3 websites, import the MP3s into iTunes, then sync my iPod.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Good Customer Support</title><link href="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/08/good-customer-support" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Good Customer Support" /><published>2023-08-31T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-12-14T20:00:04-08:00</updated><id>https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/08/good-customer-support</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/08/good-customer-support">&lt;p&gt;Having to make a phone call and talk to a companies customer support always sucks. Nowhere has this been more apparent to me than when I have been on hold for over an hour to talk to my university’s financial aid department. However, there have been some rare instances where I found my experiences almost enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;consumer-cellular&quot;&gt;Consumer Cellular&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several years ago I was helping a guy out. He got mugged and had all of his possession stolen. I decided to give him an old phone of mine, but we needed to transfer his phone number to it. So we had to call his cellular provider, consumer cellular to do so. Keep in mind, prior to this the two of us had made multiple excruciating phone calls, over the better part of a month to replace some of his lost possessions. Just to attempt to replace one of these items took multiple days worth of calls and often ended in failure. Thus, you weren’t expecting much from a single car. After a long wait (probably around 30 minutes) the two of us finally got on the line with someone. Immediately I knows this person had a southern accent which of reassuring since it meant I was not dealing with an international call center (which have never provided good service in my experience). Two are shocked and surprised, within 10 minutes we managed to get the number transferred! This is so unexpectedly quick I just had to think the representative on the phone for how great the service was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nintendo-of-america&quot;&gt;Nintendo of America&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in the previous post, I recently bought myself a used Nintendo 3DS. However, when I attempted to use my Nintendo account to access the eShop (this was before closure) I was blocked from doing so because the account of its previous owner was still tied to the console. The procedure for removing that account involved making a phone call to a Nintendo of America line for 3DS inquiries, and have a representative Remove it for me. To my surprise, not only was this line still active years after the 3DS had been discontinued (this was probably in 2021), but there was hardly any wait time to speak to someone. The person I then spoke to was super chill and completely understood why I purchased “outdated” console (purely for nostalgia). After I was done with that call, I made sure to give that representative a glowing review on the email questionnaire I was later sent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;amazon-web-services&quot;&gt;Amazon Web Services&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this day, this is the most incredible customer support experience I’ve ever had. Back in my final year of high school, I was experimenting with making an inventory app for a club I created to donate computers to low income families. Of course, I had no clue I was doing so at one point I accidentally pushed AWS IAM credential info to GitHub. Within 24 hours I got a call from the Seattle number. To my shock and awe, it was an AWS support employee who had called to inform me that they had noticed that keys tied to my account were publicly viewable on GitHub and they had deactivated them to protect my account. Suffice to say, my 18 year old mind was blown. I have issues with the way Amazon and their cloud services division sometimes conduct business, but the incredible support I received from them on that day will always stick with me and be a driving reason why I use their services.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Julian Lopez</name></author><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html">Having to make a phone call and talk to a companies customer support always sucks. Nowhere has this been more apparent to me than when I have been on hold for over an hour to talk to my university’s financial aid department. However, there have been some rare instances where I found my experiences almost enjoyable.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Finding Flags on a Website</title><link href="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/07/finding-flags-on-a-website" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finding Flags on a Website" /><published>2023-07-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-12-14T14:59:43-08:00</updated><id>https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/07/finding-flags-on-a-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/07/finding-flags-on-a-website">&lt;p&gt;A while back, I was on a website that had a weird link near the bottom that was titled “Capture the Flag”. Clicking on it, directed me to a “secret” page that described how there were six hidden flags throughout the site with in format “GXYZ{***}”. If you managed to find a flag, you could have your name added to a “hall of fame” along with the number of flags you had found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, earlier that day I had come across a blog post that had something to do with storing data within image files. On a hunch, I download an image of a flag that was on that page and opened it in Vim. To my pleasant surprise, at the end of the file there was a flag! Unfortunately I haven’t found any other flags yet, but I haven’t been trying that hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won’t be linking to this website since it would be unfair as I’ve already detailed one of the flags. That being said, a quick web search (Bing in my case) will result in many similar challenges open to all.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Julian Lopez</name></author><summary type="html">A while back, I was on a website that had a weird link near the bottom that was titled “Capture the Flag”. Clicking on it, directed me to a “secret” page that described how there were six hidden flags throughout the site with in format “GXYZ{***}”. If you managed to find a flag, you could have your name added to a “hall of fame” along with the number of flags you had found.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cleaning My 3DS</title><link href="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/05/cleaning-my-3ds" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cleaning My 3DS" /><published>2023-05-16T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-12-14T20:00:04-08:00</updated><id>https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/05/cleaning-my-3ds</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://www.julianlopez.net/posts/2023/05/cleaning-my-3ds">&lt;h2 id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table of contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#weird-problems-with-my-3ds&quot;&gt;Weird Problems with my 3DS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#cleaning-the-3ds&quot;&gt;Cleaning the 3DS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#a-new-sd-card&quot;&gt;A new SD Card&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;weird-problems-with-my-3ds&quot;&gt;Weird Problems with my 3DS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since I bought my 3DS from a retro game store&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I’ve been having some weird issues with it.
After playing a game for a while (10 minutes+), the system would freeze and I’d get an error on the bottom screen.
At first I thought this was tied to the homebrew/firmware I had installed, but I couldn’t find anything online regarding similar behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/post3/IMG_3810.jpg?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/post3/IMG_3810.jpg?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A Nintendo 3DS with a crash screen&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A Nintendo 3DS with a crash screen&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;This is what a crash would look like.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally it only had a 1 in 3 chance of turning on when you pressed the power button.
Removing the SD card and reinserting it seemed to help, but that might have been a placebo.
There were times were it look me upwards of 5 minutes to turn it on, which was especially annoying after a crash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of this, removing the SD card was a pain since the cover for the SD card slot almost never closed properly.
As a result the system would often not recognize the SD card which prevented it from booting with homebrew.
This was also just annoying at a practical level since I had to carry around my 3DS with the SD card cover slightly open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cleaning-the-3ds&quot;&gt;Cleaning the 3DS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/post3/IMG_3797.jpg?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/post3/IMG_3797.jpg?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A Nintendo 3DS with the back removed&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A Nintendo 3DS with the back removed&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;Take a good look around the screw holes.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Removing the back of the 3DS (which only took 4 phillips screws) revealed yet another problem.
There was some sort of yellowish residue around the screw holes, which was also present in between the “seams” on the bottom of the 3DS.
My best guess is that at some point the previous owner (probably a dumb kid) spilled something on it which might have damaged/broken it and sold it to the store I bought it from.
They then probably repaired it, but didn’t do a great job of cleaning it and only did the bare minimum to get it working.
Credit to that store though, they gave me a free warranty so I could have gotten it fixed for free, but given that I hacked it and was running homebrew I didn’t want to push my luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/post3/IMG_3800.jpg?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/post3/IMG_3800.jpg?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;The exposed SD card slot of a Nintendo 3DS with gunk in it&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;The exposed SD card slot of a Nintendo 3DS with gunk in it&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;A look at the gunk in the SD slot.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disassembling it further revealed that the SD card slot was also full of this gunk.
This was causing extra friction with the SD card which was why it was so hard to close the cover.
The fact that this gunk was also present here makes me think that this 3DS was submerged in some sort of liquid.
That it survived at all is probably a miracle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
    &lt;source srcset=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/post3/IMG_3803.jpg?tr=w-720,f-webp,&quot; type=&quot;image/webp&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://ik.imagekit.io/jlo64/post3/IMG_3803.jpg?tr=w-480&quot; alt=&quot;A clean disassembled Nintendo 3DS&quot; class=&quot;blog_image&quot; title=&quot;A clean disassembled Nintendo 3DS&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;The finished result.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
 &lt;/picture&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me several hours, but I got rid of any trace of the gunk.
Unfortunately, I didn’t have any rubbing alcohol (and I wasn’t crazy enough to use water) so I had to use a bunch of disposable alcohol wipes and just rub the plastic as hard as I could.
I didn’t want to touch any of the electronic stuff, but I noticed that the game cartridge slot might have had some signs of corrosion.
In the future I’ll probably try to clean that out as well, but for now I’m just happy that my 3DS is working again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-new-sd-card&quot;&gt;A new SD Card&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first hacked my 3DS I used a 128GB SD card I had been using for my Switch.
The idea was to have all the games I could ever possibly want installed on my 3DS.
However, this isn’t a great idea since the 3DS can only use 32GB SD cards by default.
While it can use larger SD cards, it generally becomes slower the larger the SD card is.
My suspicion is that the reason my 3DS was crashing was because of how slow the SD card was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully I have a friend who traded me a 32GB SD card for my 128GB one.
All I had to do to use it with my 3DS was format it to FAT32 and copy over the files from my old SD card.
The only hard part about this was that I had to delete a bunch of games to make it fit on the 32GB card.
After that it worked perfectly and I haven’t had any crashes since!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now my only problem is that I promised him I’d trade my 128GB card for it and I’ve since lost it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;Footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;GameHogs in East Los Angeles. They have by far the sketchiest storefront I’ve ever been inside, but the interior is amazing. I’ve never seen such a large selection of games, much less retro games! Highly recommend if you’re in the area. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Julian Lopez</name></author><category term="3ds" /><summary type="html">Table of contents Weird Problems with my 3DS Cleaning the 3DS A new SD Card Footnotes</summary></entry></feed>